Finding aid for the Red Bird, Oklahoma glass plate negatives LSC.1838
UCLA Library Special Collections
Red Bird, Oklahoma glass plate negatives
1900-1910
UCLA Library Special Collections
Red Bird Investment Company
LSC.1838
12 items (12 glass plate negatives)
Red Bird is located in Wagoner County, Oklahoma. The town was settled before 1900 by the Barber and Ruffin families. Collection consists of a group of 12 original glass plate negatives, depicting early views of homes, businesses and townspeople in the all black town of Red Bird, Oklahoma.
Restrictions on Access
Stored off-site. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9975427723606533
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Purchase, 2009.
Biography/History
Red Bird is located in Wagoner County, Oklahoma. The town was settled before 1900.
Scope and Content
Group of twelve 5 inch by 7 inch glass plate negatives, depicting early views of homes, businesses and townspeople in the all black town of Red Bird, OK. Images include a grain elevator, a grocery store and a railroad station.
Online Items Available
This collection has been digitized and is available online: Red Bird, Oklahoma glass plate negatives (12 items).
Black-and-white negatives.; African Americans -- Oklahoma -- Red Bird.; Red Bird (Okla.).; Storefronts -- Oklahoma -- Red Bird.; Railroad stations -- Oklahoma -- Red Bird.; Farmhouses -- Oklahoma -- Red Bird.
- Farmhouse in Red Bird, Oklahoma, [circa 1906?]; 5 in x 7 in glass plate negative
  Scope and Content
  A man in overalls and two women standing on the porch of a farmhouse.
- Farmhouse in Red Bird, Oklahoma, [circa 1906?]
  Double exposure with two houses (or two views of the same house?) visible and two figures posing in front.
- Farmhouse in Red Bird, Oklahoma, [circa 1906?]
  Farmhouse in a field.
- Farmhouse in Red Bird, Oklahoma, [circa 1906?]
- Farmhouse in Red Bird, Oklahoma, [circa 1906?]
  A farmhouse with an African American child visible on the side porch behind chicken wire.
- Farmhouse with family on porch in Red Bird, Oklahoma, [circa 1906?]
  African American family posed on front porch with a dog sitting outside of a picket fence.
- Grain elevator in Red Bird, Oklahoma, [circa 1906?]
  A grain elevator, utility pole, several small buildings, a barn and scattered pipes.
- Grocery store in Red Bird, Oklahoma, [circa 1906?]
  Six African American men sitting outside of a grocery store. Signs in the windows advertise the sale of dry goods, notions, groceries, and cigars.
- House and stores in Red Bird, Oklahoma, [circa 1906?]
  Double exposure showing men and women of Red Bird standing in front of a house with a carriage. The fainter exposure shows a store with a sign advertising tobacco.
- Railroad Station in Red Bird, Oklahoma, [circa 1906?]
  Automobile with man in driver's seat and four children in the back seat parked in front of a railroad station.
- Railroad Station in Red Bird, Oklahoma, [circa 1906?]
- Stores in Red Bird, Oklahoma, [circa 1906?]
  Six men pose in front of a store front while two other figures lean out of a window in an adjacent building. Signs on the storefronts advertise Arm & Hammer Soda; Kantrip overalls, jumpers, and pants; and smoking & chewing tobaccos.